Definitions
-----------

Encapsulation: Combining variables and methods (code to run an operation) together. E.g. A data form which takes in information about a person, using a scanner, and prints it out to the screen, with any neccersary loops or catches to alert incorrectly entered values in the fields, and to direct correct input.

Inheritance: Code reused from one or more classes. E.g. If an algorithm had to perform a calculation in one class, and all/part of the algorithm was needed again in another class, but with different initial values, the code could be inherited from the original algorithm.

Polymorphism: One action can occur in multiple forms. E.g. Input ticket types for some transport (bus, train etc.), output various ticket types and prices.

Abstraction: Only functionality is visiable to the user, implementation is covered up. E.g. A person writing an email inputs the recieving address, the message, attachments and other options, then sends. The coded details of taking in the input, and sending the email, are hidden from the user.